原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  亲爱的小饭  斑驳  洗七里
翻译:  油腻希  冰蓝  翻译事业帝王赛
校对:  新浪微博@赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第九季 第六集
看啊  量子涨落
Behold the Quantum Flux --
量子涨落
是在空间任意位置对于能量的暂时变化
通往过去的魔法大门
a magic portal to the past,
有些人称之为"时间机器"
what some might call a "Time machine."
你们该"哇"了
This is where you guys go "Oooh."
-不要  谢谢  -继续吧
- No, thank you. - Just get on with it.
是的  "哇"
"Ooh," Indeed.
我在办爸爸和歌洛莉亚的结婚十周年纪念派对
I'm throwing Dad and Gloria's 10th anniversary party,
而菲尔是部分娱乐项目
and Phil is part of the entertainment.
我要让歌洛莉亚在众人面前消失
I'm gonna make Gloria seemingly dematerialize,
然后令人惊奇地穿越到过去
then wondrously travel back through time,
最后穿着婚纱重新出现
and then rematerialize in her wedding dress.
她要在箱子里换衣服
She's gonna change her clothes in a box.
所以我对你在台上介绍我这事很紧张
This is why I'm nervous about you introducing me.
我开玩笑的  你会表现得很棒的
I'm kidding! You're gonna be great.
他最好发挥出色
He better be great.
我希望爸爸和歌洛莉亚的派对十分完美
I want Dad and Gloria's party to be perfect.
当年我在婚礼上还挺讨人厌的
I was kind of a pill at their wedding.
我那时候还没完全接受歌洛莉亚
I hadn't fully accepted Gloria yet.
而且我觉得我亲妈会如此下场我有一点责任
And I feel a little responsible for what happened with my mom.
我在婚宴上灌了她三杯
I fed her, like, three drinks at the reception.
想缓和一下气氛嘛
You know, just to take the edge off.
我是歌洛莉亚  吻我  快吻我
I'm Gloria! Kiss me! Oh, hey, kiss me!
不  天啊
No, no! Oh, geez!
妈妈
Mom! Mom!
她差点就把门框都扯掉了
She almost took the doorframe off.
她进入了虫洞
Into the wormhole she goes.
时钟倒转
Clocks turn backwards,
日历重新一页页恢复
calendar pages re-attach themselves,
看呀
and behold!
美丽的新娘
The beautiful bride!
各位  你们不觉得激动吗
Guys! This isn't exciting to you?
用一下想象力啊
Use your imaginations.
脑补到时候是我站在穿着新娘服的
Picture me standing next to Gloria
歌洛莉亚旁边
in a wedding dress.
就这样吧
We're done.
米奇尔  你取蛋糕了吗
Mitchell, did you get the cake?
嗯  我都搞定了
Yeah, yeah. I got everything.
好  我得在爸爸家跟你碰头
Okay, good. I'll have to meet you at Dad's.
我得跟菲尔一起去取魔法箱子
I need to go with Phil to pick up his magic box.
你跟菲尔说了
Oh, and, hey, you told Phil
别跟小卡提变魔术的事  对吧
not to mention the trick to Cam, right?
如果小卡发现了  他会想让
If Cam finds out, he's just gonna want us
我俩也表演一番的
to do some kind of performance, too.
我蛮确定跟他说了别告诉小卡
Pretty sure I told him not to say anything.
我蛮确定你没跟他说
Yeah, pretty sure you didn't.
这是要干嘛
So, uh, what's all this?
这是补偿
This is redemption.
给我个直接的答案就好
Maybe just a straight answer.
那年是2007年
The year was 2007 --
杰和歌洛莉亚的婚宴
the wedding reception of Jay and Gloria.
我们送新婚夫妇的礼物是二重唱
Our gift to the newlyweds was a duet performance
-《溪中小岛》  -《溪中小岛》
- of "Islands in the Stream." - "Islands in the Stream."
没送成这份礼物  因为
A gift that would never be, because...
我记得
I remember.
我在婚宴上灌了我妈妈几杯
I fed my mom a few drinks at the reception.
我真的不想唱歌  所以我想
I really did not want to sing, so I figured
如果我把她灌醉  我就没必要表演了
if I got her a little tipsy, I wouldn't have to perform
因为我得握着她的手
because I'd have to hold her hand...
不  天啊
No, no, no! Oh, geez!
妈妈
Mom, Mom!
之后挽着她的头发让她吐
...and later hold her hair back.
你家人想象了十年  如果表演了会怎样
Well, your family has wondered for 10 years "What if?"
今天  他们将得知答案
Today, they find out what for.
我不确定  小卡
Mm, I don't know, Cam.
我有些生疏了
I'm a little rusty,
在帐篷里音响效果也不好
and acoustics are never good inside a tent.
还有  这场派对的重点不是我们
And -- Oh! This party isn't about us.
会有许多表演者
There's a whole slate of performers.
歌洛莉亚要在箱子里换衣服
Gloria's changing in a box.
这让我们的歌曲串烧更受欢迎了
Which makes our medley all the more welcome.
现在成了歌曲串烧吗  不
It's a medley now? No! No.
我今天绝对不可能以任何形态
In no way, shape, or form
或者形式在我挑剔的家人面前表演
am I performing today in front of my judgmental family.
好吧  我们就这么去派对吧
Fine. We'll just... go to the party.
谢谢
Thank you.
-不要歌曲串烧  -没错
- No medley. ‭- Exactly.
等等  这不是什么陷阱吧
Wait. This isn't a trick --
就三首没联系的歌曲
Just three un-related songs.
你刚同意了  彩排现在开始
You just agreed. Rehearsal starts right now.
准备好了就加入
Jump in when you're ready.
为什么是你在做饭
Why are you cooking?
妈妈有允许你待在这吗
Are you allowed back there?
这是我们的结婚纪念日
It's our anniversary.
我不能为你妈妈做点好事吗
Can't I do something nice for your mother?
也许吧
Maybe.
早安  美女
Morning, beautiful.
早餐有西式的煎鸡蛋  辣香肠  玉米薄饼
We have huevos, we have chorizo, we have tortilla.
唯一缺的只有曼尼
What we ain't got is Manny.
很遗憾  他今天不会出席派对
Unfortunately, he's gonna be a no-show at the party today.
我有何能为你做的
What can I get you?
把这些垃圾从我身边拿开
Take that garbage away from me.
我要去散步
I'm going for a walk.
曼尼是我们婚礼的一大亮点
Manny was a big part of our wedding.
他牵着歌洛莉亚走上通道  还表演书法
He walked Gloria down the aisle, did the calligraphy.
我知道他不参加我们的周年派对
And I knew him not showing up to our anniversary party
会让歌洛莉亚心情很不好
would put Gloria in a bad mood.
某种程度来说  我觉得自己有责任
In some ways, I feel responsible.
你又回来了吗
You're home again?
你都上大学了
You're in college.
你不能每周末都回家啊
You can't come back every weekend!
-都不拥抱一下吗  -我爱你
-So no hug? ‭-  I love you,
但是你老待在这里  就不能最大程度地
but you're not making the most of your college experience
体验到大学生活了
by being here all the time.
我大一时  我父亲送我去学校
My father dropped me off my freshman year,
我一直到来年春天才再见到他
and I didn't see him again till the spring.
-想知道为什么吗  -我不知道
- You want to know why? - I don't know.
跟姑娘和打架有关吗
Something about dames and fistfights?
没错  我忙于交朋友
Exactly -- too busy making friends,
泡妞之类的事情
chasing skirts, and things of that nature.
但你母亲和我认为  总待在家里
But your mother and I think it's bad for you
对你没好处
to be here all the time.
所以赶紧走吧
So hit the road,
我们感恩节再见
and we'll see you at Thanksgiving.
等等  我被禁止进入自己的房子了吗
Wait. I'm banned from my house?
别这样想
Don't think of it that way.
你是被禁止进入我的房子
You're banned from my house.
严格说来  歌洛莉亚没参与这一决定
Technically, Gloria was not in on this decision,
意思就是
in the sense that...
她不知道这个决定
she was not in on this decision.
我有点在闹脾气
I was a little grumpy.
我同意在派对上跟菲尔一起
I had agreed to do this magic trick
表演这个魔术
at the party with Phil.
我要进入一个箱子里
I go into a box,
然后穿着我的婚纱出来
and then I come out in my wedding dress.
但是有个问题
But there was a problem.
拉
Pull!
拉不动啊
She won't budge!
唯一合理的解释就是
The only logical explanation
有人溜进了我的衣柜
is that somebody snuck into my closet
把我的婚纱缩小了
and shrunk my wedding dress.
比如我妹妹
Like, probably my sister.
所以过去这周
So for the past week,
我在努力减肥
I've had to, like, get even skinnier
要比我结婚时还要瘦
than I was at my wedding.
你闭嘴
Oh, shut up.
飚眼先生的幻想殿堂
别丢人
Be cool.
菲尔  这是魔术商店
Phil, it's a magic shop.
我是来过这店里最不丢人的那个人了
I'm the coolest person that's ever been in here.
他怎么做到的
How does he do it?
我开玩笑的  我知道他怎么弄的
I'm kidding. I know how he does it.
克莱尔  这位就是传奇的飙眼先生
Claire, meet the legendary Mister Ekshun.
你好
Hello.
你耳朵后面是什么
And what's this behind your ear?
毛衣掉毛了而已
Oh, just some sweater fluff.
这地方太棒了
Well, the place looks great.
你能想象天天来这里吗
Can you imagine coming here every day?
真希望是每天都来
I wish it was every day.
我现在那么多巡演要去
I have less and less time for the old Illusionatorium,
越来越没时间打理幻想殿堂了
with all the road jobs I still book.
你可以快速再给我过一遍
Would you mind quickly walking me through
量子涨落魔术吗
the Quantum Flux Illusion?
根据魔术表演法则
Well, according to magic bylaws,
有无执照魔术师在场时
I can't disclose the secret
我不能泄露表演秘密
in the presence of a non-licensed magician.
没问题  我可以去外面
Not a problem. I can just step outside.
胡说
Nonsense!
我们早有准备
We prepare for such things.
五感剥夺头盔
The old sensory-deprivation helmet.
我一戴上这玩意儿
Oh! ‭I put that baby on,
就感觉好像我没有室友似的
it's almost like I don't have roommates.
没错  我...我说过了  可以去外...
Yeah, I, like I said, could just step out--
去外面就可以
Outside would be fine.
她真可爱
She's lovely.
是啊  我超幸运的
Yeah. I'm super lucky.
太感谢你肯帮我了
Thank you so much for helping me with this.
你逗呢
Are you kidding?
要不是你几年前
I wouldn't have this life
推掉了伊斯塔帕游艇上的魔术演出
if you hadn't turned down the magician gig
我根本不可能过上现在的生活
on that Ixtapa cruise years ago.
什么  从来没人找我啊
What? I-I was never offered that job.
是啊  他们说给你打电话  但是都没人接
Yeah, they said they called you and never heard back,
所以他们就来找我了
so they moved on to me.
我根本没接到那电话啊
I never got that call!
我不能呼吸了  我不能呼吸了
I couldn't breathe! I couldn't breathe!
你忘开通风口了
Well, you forgot to turn on the ventilator.
这工作应该是我来做吗
That was supposed to be my job?
不
No.
这本该是我的工作
This was supposed to be my job.
我看起来好蠢
I look stupid.
你看到你妈心情有多差了吧
Hey, you see what a bad mood your mother's in?
那是因为她想念曼尼
That's because she misses Manny.
今天  你就是曼尼
Today, you're Manny.
那她不就会想乔吗
But wouldn't she miss Joe then?
别想多了
Don't overthink.
赶紧进去  装着心里难受
Just go in there, act all heartsick,
告诉她你想喝下午茶
and tell her you want to have high tea.
妈  为什么女孩都是迷啊
Hey, Mom. Why are girls such a mystery?
来个司康饼吧
Have a scone!
出去  我根本见不得那个
Get out of here. I cannot even look at that.
要命
Yikes!
没关系  没事
Shake it off. That's okay.
第一次尝试已经不错啦
That's a good first try.
去拿他的排笛
Go grab his pan flute!
我的新娘怎么样啦
How's my bride?
现在都这么大了
Ay! So big now.
我知道  我也感觉到了
I know. It snuck up on me, too.
但请记住  放弃也是生命的自然过程
But remember, letting go is a natural part of life.
不是  杰  那样一点也不好
No. It's terrible, Jay.
让乔送司康饼进来就更糟了
And sending Joe in here with scones made it worse!
安静点  弗汉希欧
Silencio, Fulgencio!
♪ 古老的黑魔法咒语锁困了我心 ♪
♪ That old black magic has me in its spell ♪
That old black magic - Ella Fitzgerald
♪ 你的古老黑魔法令我意乱情迷 ♪
♪ That old black magic that you weave so well ♪
到你了  老爸
Take it, Daddy!
米奇尔  你知道吗  我换了莉莉
Oh! Hi, Mitchell. You know what -- I def traded up with Lily.
还好你退出了
I'm glad you backed out.
莉莉  去让你的美妙声带休息下
Lily, why don't you go rest your instrument?
那我就解析一下这个绝妙计划吧
So, uh, just to break down this "foolproof" plan,
你以为这样我就会嫉妒
you thought this would make me so jealous
然后我就会求你让我参演  是吧
that I'd beg to be back in the act, didn't you?
不  我就是发现了与我超合拍的小天才
Um, no. I just found a younger talent that I clicked with.
好吧  很期待你俩的表演
Okay, well, I look forward to watching you two perform.
我超羡慕你有机会看我们的表演
Well, I envy you getting to watch us perform.
莉莉  宝贝  快来
Lily, sweetheart, get in here!
排练还没结束呢
The rehearsal's not over!
时间不等人  我的小歌星
Y-Y-Yeah, time's a-wasting, my little thrush!
快  派对快开始啦
And hurry! The party starts real soon!
好吧  你赢了
Okay, you know what? You win.
你知道我是绝不会带那乌鸦嗓上台的
You know I'm never taking the stage with that screech owl.
唱吧
Just sing.
这对你来说很重要的
It would be very important for you.
-对我吗  -是的
- For me? - ‭Yes.
你家人深深着迷我的演出好多次了
Your family has been entranced by my performances many times.
这表演对我可有可无  但在过去的10年里
I don't need this, but over the last 10 years,
我一直看着你在他们面前胆怯
I've watch you shrink in their presence.
你很喜欢唱歌呀
And you love to sing.
就还好吧
I like it fine.
我们出去的时候  你总是第一个
And when we go out, you're the first person
抢过话筒  一唱就是一晚
to grab the karaoke mic and scat the night away,
而且你唱得很好呢
and you're good at it.
你知道人们怎么称呼你吗
You know what people are calling you?
男版艾拉·费兹洁拉
"Fella Fitzgerald."
知名黑人爵士女歌手  人称爵士乐第一夫人
也曾唱过"That old black magic"
他们才没有呢
They do not!
有的
Yes, they do.
就一次  我想看到你在你家人面前
And just once, I would love to watch your talent soar
大展才华  让他们永远闭嘴
in front of your family and shut them up for good.
-但如果你不想去...  -管他呢
- But if you don't want to -- - You know what? Screw it.
虽然我也很确定
I don't even care that I'm
你现在就是在拐我  但我不在乎
mostly sure you're manipulating me right now.
我们表演定了
We're doing this.
我就知道你会回心转意  欢迎回来演出
I knew you'd come around. Welcome back to the act.
但这就对我有点太过了
Okay, now, this is a bit much for me.
那...
So...
大胡子  你看到曼尼·迪尔加多了吗
Hey, Beardy. Have you seen Manny Delgado?
我想那位花花公子正忙着呢
I think the make-out king is a little occupied.
你没看到代表"有事"的领带吗
Have you no respect for the ascot?!
你来这干嘛
What are you doing here?
我需要你来参加我们周年派对
I need you to come to our anniversary party.
我以为我不受欢迎[西语]呢
I thought I was persona non grata.
现在我就快要得手[西语]了
Now I'm halfway into flagrante delicto.
这个  我可不会错过
This, I don't miss.
你不来  你妈很伤心呢
Your mother is upset you're not gonna be there.
谁让她当初不让我回家
Well, then maybe she shouldn't have banished me from the house.
我可能不小心让你相信
I may have accidently led you to believe
她也有份做这个决定
that she was part of that decision,
-但实际上...  -我就知道
- when actually -- ‭- I knew it!
我就知道我妈不会这么对她的宝贝儿子[西语]
I knew my mom wouldn't be that mean to her little papi.
曼尼
Manny?
马上  亲爱的
One minute, baby.
-这居然有妞喜欢  -闭嘴
- That's been working? - Shut up.
因为你  我冷落了我妈一周
So, I've been icing my mother for a week because of you?
她肯定觉得我是最差的儿子
She must think I'm the worst son.
那就回家让她开心
Then come home and make her day.
我才不会丢下这些  回家救你一命呢
I'm not dropping everything to come home and bail you out.
或许明天可以  而且我要告诉她
Tomorrow, maybe -- and I'm telling her
-你是我不回去的原因  -等下等下
- you're the reason I haven't been around. - Hold on. Hold on.
她通过我知道这件事比较好
It's better if she hears it from me.
我得变个说法
I just have to spin it
说成我这么做是为你好就行了
as if it's something I did in your best interest.
而我还得支持你的鬼话
And I'm supposed to back that up
装出一副这样对我更好的样子...
like I'm somehow better off because --
你去哪呢  熊宝宝
Where'd you go, baby bear?
这就来  熊宝宝
Coming, baby bear.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
但怎么两个人都叫熊宝宝
But two baby bears?
我还是新手
I'm new at this.
克莱尔  问你个小问题
Hey, Claire. Quick question.
我看到你只安排了米奇和我唱一首歌
I see that you only have Mitch and I down for one song.
这不够讲一个完整的故事
Which isn't enough time to tell a story.
我们愿意把歌单缩减到六首歌
So we would be willing to cut our set list to six songs.
好  那就一首吧
Cool. So we'll keep it at one?
好吧  那五首短的呢
Okay, so five quick songs, then?
-一首  -这样吧  你现在答应
- One song. ‭- Yeah, I would be willing
我就同意只表演三首歌
to close this right now at three songs.
一首短的
One quick song,
如果你企图开始介绍乐队成员
and if you so much as begin to introduce the band,
我就切断电源
I'll cut the power off.
你怎么能用这个态度和表演者说话
Okay, that is not the way you talk to talent.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?
我在卫生间  进来吧
I'm in the bathroom! Come in!
我是菲尔
I-It's Phil.
进来
Come in!
菲尔·邓菲
Phil Dunphy.
菲尔
Phil!
裙子在那边的防尘袋里
The dress is in that bag over there.
太好了  我会藏到时间机器的夹层里的
Oh, great. I'll hide it in the back of the time machine.
你...
You, uh...
你这是在为摔跤比赛做准备吗
You got a big wrestling match coming up?
我今天不太顺遂
I am having a bad day.
我没心情唠家常
I don't feel like doing the chitchatting.
我今天也过得不太好
Not having a great day myself.
我十五年前错过了一通电话
Missed a phone call 15 years ago
那本能展开我身为魔术师的第二事业
that could have launched a second career as a magician.
我本能拥有一切
I could've had it all.
白天是房产经纪人  晚上是魔术师
Realtor by day, magician by night.
就像那部我没写完的摇滚歌剧的主人公一样
Just like the hero of that rock opera I never finished.
菲尔  我说了我没心情唠家常
Phil, this feels like the chitchatting.
我或许该走了
Well, I should probably get going.
这些蒸汽会让我的西装起皱
The steam's starting to pucker up my suit.
做完了
Done.
我参加你婚礼时穿的就是这身西装
It's the same suit I wore to your wedding.
真不敢相信变得这么宽松了
Can't believe how loose it's gotten.
我很荣幸地向大家介绍
And now it is my pleasure to bring up
我们的第一对特别演出嘉宾
the first of our very special entertainers.
他们将带来一首歌
Here to perform one song,
卡梅隆和米奇尔
Cameron and Mitchell.
放松
Just relax.
好的  记得  这和卡拉OK一样
Okay, now, remember -- it's just like karaoke.
是  是  我明白我明白
Yeah, yeah, I-I got it. I got it.
唱两句就转到我的鼓独奏
Sing a little and then throw to the drum solo.
好的好的
Okay. Okay.
♪ 古老的黑魔法咒语锁困了我心 ♪
♪ That old black magic has me in its spell ♪
♪ 你的古老黑魔法令我意乱情迷 ♪
♪ That old black magic that you weave so well ♪
♪ 冰冷的手指沿着我的脊背上下乱爬 ♪
♪ Icy fingers up and down my spine ♪
♪ 当我们四目相对  就是那古老的黑魔法 ♪
♪ The same old witchcraft when your eyes meet mine ♪
来一段  钢琴师
Take it, piano guy!
瞧他表演多好
Look at him go.
要知道  他小时候就是个妈宝
You know, he was raised a mama's boy.
现在他是个强壮  有能力的男人
Now he's a strong, capable man
嘴里发出奇怪的声音  听起来像乐器似的
making nonsense noises that sound a lot like instruments.
让我们听听吉他的动静
Let's hear that guitar weep!
我们还有一个人的声音没听到
And there is someone that we haven't heard from yet.
陪我来一段  贝司先生
Take a walk with me, Mr. Bass Man.
♪ 面对黑魔法  我又有什么办法 ♪
♪ What do you do when faced with black magic? ♪
谢谢大家  非常感谢
Thank you! Thank you so much!
再来一...
One more ti-
好吧  没了
Okay. Nope.
太谢谢你们了
Thank you very much.
你们真[西语]好
Uh, muy kind,
但我知道你们这样只是为了让我好[西语]受
pero I know you're only doing it to make me feel mas better.
看来你在车里没少听西语教程
Somebody's been listening to Rosetta Stone in the car.
小卡  别这样  有话别憋着
Cam, come on. Talk to me.
你他叽哩哇啦的是怎么回事
What in the skibbity doo wop was that?
你自己带了一票摄影棚现场观众吗
Did you bring your own studio audience?
不是  他们是歌洛莉亚的家人
No. They're Gloria's family.
和某些人不同  他们是有感情的
Unlike some people, they feel things.
小卡  抱歉  我有点忘形了
Cam, look, I'm sorry. I got carried away.
感觉你是故意伤我
It seemed deliberately hurtful.
每个音乐家都得到了独奏的机会
Every musician got a solo
只除了你对他立过婚誓的那一个
except the one you promised to have and to hold.
能别打岔吗
Okay, do you mind?
谢谢合作
Thank you.
小卡  很抱歉我忘了给你独奏的机会
Look, Cam, I-I'm sorry I forgot to throw it to you,
但我当时只是太投入了
but I-I was just swept up in the moment.
那场面令我太陶醉了
It -- That was -- It was exhilarating.
我...  你听到那些人欢呼了吗
I-I -- Did you hear those people cheering?
你确实表演得很精彩
Well... you were brilliant.
虽说不是最慷慨无私的表演  但仍然...
Not the most generous of performances, but --
我在我爱评头论足的家人面前完全无拘无束
I was completely free in front of my entire judgy family,
而这一切都归功于你
and none of that would have happened without you.
我想我听懂你的意思了
Well, I think I hear what you're saying --
你是说有一半的掌声是属于我的
that half of that applause was mine
-因为我让你蜕变了  -好吧
- 'cause I transformed you. - Okay.
这比任何10分钟的鼓手独奏都要好
Well, that's better than any 10-minute drum solo.
你会告诉大家这都是我的功劳吗
So you'll tell everyone this was my doing?
当然了
Of course I will.
过来
Come here.
好了  到时我会把箱子转两次
Okay, I'll spin the box two times,
你有30秒时间换上婚纱
you'll have 30 seconds to change into your wedding dress.
或者我可以换上旧睡衣
Or I change into an old pair of pajamas
让大家知道我和杰在一起后
to show the people how comfortable
有多自在多舒服
I have always been with Jay.
好啊  歌洛莉亚
Oh, yeah. Sure, Gloria.
不如我们把台本扔了
Why don't we just throw the script out
你想说什么就随便说好了
and you can say whatever you want,
反正观众都觉得
'cause the audience already thinks
演员在乱编故事了
the actors make it all up anyway?!
对不起
I'm sorry!
怎么回事
What's going on?
没事的  菲尔
It's okay, Phil.
他很难过  因为15年前
He's very upset because 15 years ago,
他错过了一通叫他去船上变魔术的电话
he missed a phone call for a job to do boat magic.
你整个下午都在生闷气就为了这事啊
That's why you've been sulking all afternoon?
我的生活本来会完全不同
My life would be completely different
都怪愚蠢的命运
if not for stupid fate!
命运
Fate?
我来问你个问题
Let me ask you something.
好好学习这宝贵的一课
And there's a real lesson here.
你喜欢你现在的生活吗
Do you like how your life turned out?
喜欢
Yeah, sure.
家人超棒  工作稳定  公交椅广告
Great family, steady work, bus benches?
你不在家时我接到了那通电话
I got that call when you weren't home
但一直没告诉你
and never gave you the message.
什么  问号加感叹号
What -- question mark, exclamation point?!
你为什么要那么做
Why would you do something like that?!
为了救他  不让他被自己害惨
To save him from himself.
有时候人需要被轻推一把
People sometimes need a gentle nudge
才能做出正确的决定
to make the right choice.
大家很幸运  因为有我担任这个角色
And, luckily for everyone, I'm here to do it.
不只是推了菲尔
And not just for Phil.
我知道你在想曼尼为什么没来
I know you're wondering why Manny isn't here.
-我敢打赌...  -谁准备好看魔术表演啦
- I b-- - ‭Who's ready for some magic?
菲尔  歌洛莉亚  该你们上场了
Phil, Gloria, you're up.
-老公  你还好吧  -不好
- Honey, you okay? - ‭Nope!
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
科学家会告诉你们
the scientists would have you believe
时间旅行纯属鬼扯
that time travel is poppycock.
在人最好的歌洛莉亚与杰这人的大日子上
But today, on the anniversary of the wonderful Gloria and Jay,
我将驳倒那些质疑的声音
I shall confound the skeptics
将这位美丽的女子
and transport this beautiful woman
送回她举行婚礼那一天
back in time to the day of her wedding.
歌洛莉亚  请入箱
Gloria, get in the box!
麻烦来点鼓声
Drumroll, please.
好赞  打鼓
Whoo! Yes, drums!
超棒
Yes!
看  她消失在虫洞里了
Anyway, watch as she disappears into the wormhole.
这就是我的魔术  我表演完了
That's my trick. I'm done.
你表演完了是什么意思  把她带回来啊
What do you mean, you're done? Bring her back.
我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready!
你让我的梦想消失了
You made my dream disappear.
现在你的也消失了
Now yours is gone.
有人吗  我想出来
Hola! I want to come out!
菲尔  菲尔  你在"迪迪"我的派对
Phil. Phil, you are Dede-ing my party.
你爸爸"迪迪"了我的人生
Your father Dede'd my life.
15年前那通叫我去表演的电话是他接的
He's the one who got the phone call 15 years ago
但却从没转告过我
about the magic job and never told me.
-菲尔  -你家人一直把我当小孩对待
- Oh, Phil. - Your family has always treated me like a child
好像我无法自己做决定
who can't make his own decisions.
连我出席婚礼该穿什么
I couldn't even make an outfit choice for the wedding
你妈妈都要指手画脚
without your mother commenting on it.
所以我当年才偷给了她三杯酒
That's why I slipped her those three drinks at the reception.
这里面好热呀
It's very warm back here!
你必须把歌洛莉亚从箱子里放出来
You need to let Gloria out of that box.
还有
And...
那件事与我爸无关
my dad had nothing to do with that.
是我让他别转告你留言的
I'm the one who told him not to give you the message.
是我没听见"请看"吗
‭Did I miss the "Ta-da"?
菲尔  对不起
Phil, I'm so sorry.
但当时你的工作刚有起色
But your business was just taking off,
而孩子们都还小
and the kids were really little.
不  别说了  我不想听到
No, no. I-I -- I don't want to hear it.
原来我老婆才是我不能有魔术事业的凶手
My own wife is the reason I don't have a career in magic --
这我生来就为此的事业
a thing I was born to do?!
快看我
Look at me!
我十年来一点都没变
I haven't changed in 10 years!
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
你来了  太好了
You came! Thank God!
不是为了你
Not because of you.
想到我妈妈需要我
I couldn't enjoy my time with Denise
我也没办法好好享受跟丹尼丝共处的时光
knowing my mother needed me.
我有稍微享受到一点啦
I mean, I enjoyed it a little.
她是个想用热情取代暴食的舞蹈专业妹子
She's a dance major trying to replace food with affection.
我真的无所谓
I really don't care.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
我有个惊喜给你
I have a surprise for you!
我来了
I'm here!
好吧
Okay.
本来还以为会有大一点的反应呢
I was kind of expecting a bigger reaction.
我也以为曼尼来了就能让你负担一轻呢
Yeah, I thought for sure Manny being here would tip the scales.
我才不用谁让我一轻
No! I don't need anyone to do that for me!
别来烦我
Just leave me alone.
你们俩又在玩什么变态把戏了
What kind of sick game are you two playing?
你们到底懂没懂我来这里是放弃了什么啊
Do you have any idea what I gave up to be here?
歌洛莉亚  你到底怎么了
What's going on with you, Gloria?
人家现在穿不下这婚纱了
This dress doesn't fit me anymore!
就因为这个吗
That's it?!
我大老远去曼尼宿舍只是白费功夫吗
I drove all the way to Manny's dorm for nothing?
对对对  你今天牺牲最大了
Oh, because you've made the sacrifice today.
你不懂啦
You don't understand.
我总跟别人说我很努力
I tell people that I work hard
来保持体态与保持年轻
to stay fit and to stay young,
但事实上我几乎没下过什么功夫
but the reality is that I barely do anything.
但现在人家的身体越来越...
But now my body is getting...
胖了吗
Bigger?
你好大的胆子
How dare you!
不过是啦
But yes.
但我一直拥有某种外形体态
But I've always looked a certain way.
现在我走形  那我还是什么
And now that I don't, then what am I?
就只是一个有辣酱生意的自学美发师
Just a self-trained hairdresser with a hot-sauce business.
那生意还在啊
You still have that?
歌洛莉亚  你绝不只是你的外表那么简单
Gloria, you're so much more than how you look.
这种话是说来给
That's what you say to people
人老珠黄的女人听的
that are not that pretty anymore.
你是不是傻啦
Are you insane?
你就算是我这个年纪而且再重14公斤
You could be my age and 30 pounds heavier,
对我来说也还是不可高攀的尤物
and you would still be unbelievably out of my league.
听我说  你重了一点  那又怎么样啊
Listen, you gain a couple -- who cares?
过去十年是我人生最美好的一段日子
These have been the best 10 years of my life.
而每一斤肉  每一条皱纹
I'm in it for every pound, every wrinkle,
每一根白发都有我的影子
every gray hair.
要不要这样
Come on!
走  上车
Let's go. Get in the car.
-我们要去哪里  -这就不用你担心了
- Where are we going? - Don't worry about it.
也是  我何须现在开始自己做决定呢
Oh. Why should I start making my own decisions now?
没告诉你那份工作  我很抱歉
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about the job.
但你就是那种"有梦就追"的人
You're just such a "go for it" kind of guy --
我也很爱你这点
and I love that about you --
但当时  我们有三个嗷嗷待哺的孩子
but in that case, we had three little kids,
有房贷要付  我心里慌嘛
a mortgage, and I was nervous.
但好歹你做决定时可以带上我吧
You could have at least included me in the decision.
你说得对  你说得没错
You're right! You're right.
我也知道一句"我很抱歉"并没有用
And I know "I'm sorry" doesn't begin to cover it.
为什么停下了
Why are we stopping?
我们的孩子都长大了
Well, our kids are grown,
我经营一家公司  你白天工作也很棒
I run a company, you've got a great day job.
我觉得或许是时候让你重拾往日爱好了
I thought maybe it was time you picked up an old hobby.
那是...
Are those -- Uh...
你的新魔术用品店钥匙
Keys to your new magic shop.
我的老天啊
Oh, my God!
去吧
Go on!
-不是吧  -没错
- What?! - ‭I know!
飙眼先生十分乐意地以接近白送价格转让
And Mister Ekshun was willing to let it go for next to nothing.
现在我仔细想想
Which, now that I think of it,
这好像不是个好兆头
is probably not a great sign.
这也太赞了
This is awesome!
"表演[飙眼]先生"的哏  我现在才发现啊
And "Mister Ekshun" -- I just got that!
其实挺好笑的  你用来补偿
It's kind of funny that you're making up
私自替我做决定的方法
for making a decision that should have been mine
就是私自替我做了另一个决定
by making another decision for me.
你是想要还是不想要
Do you want it or not?
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- I love you. ‭- I love you.
法则规定
Bylaws.